Thaer Shakhshir

Orléans, ON

(709) 330-2846 • thaer.shakhshir7@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/tshakhshir

System Analyst / Quality Assurance

Summary

Knowledgeable IT support technician with 4 - 5 years of experience assisting customers with Hardware and Software related issues. Provided rigorous 1st and 2nd Tiers technical Support to clients. Enlightened in networking principles, protocols and applications. Known for exceptional written and oral communication, time management, teamwork, and multitasking skills. Earned a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science, in addition to various professional certificates.

Highlights

• Linux Terminal

- Proficient troubleshooter
 JavaScript
- SQL DB Management

Cybersecurity

CompTIA A+

- FileZilla
- HTML

QA Software testing
 Ticketing Systems

- AWS
- Python

Virtualization

Azure

Windows 10

Microsoft Office Suite 365

Work Experience

Technical Support Engineer

Check Point Software Technologies, Ltd. - Ottawa, Canada

2021 - Present

- Research, diagnose, troubleshoot, and resolve customer issues in an accurate and timely manner
- Work with different systems, software, and hardware and follow fixed procedures to escalate unresolved issues
- Track and triage customer support cases and Interact with customers for analysis and resolution
- Collaborate with software engineers to help resolve problems
- Engage with the company's internal resources, knowledge base and admin guides to implement resolutions

Junior Support Engineer

2019 - 2020

Unlimi-Tech Software Inc - Ottawa, Canada

- Provided 1st and 2nd tier support to clients via Kayako ticketing software and live chat
- Consulted software guides and support portals to implement fixes and updates on Support Tickets
- Replicated customer issues in a test environment and verified resolutions to meet client expectations
- Performed QA testing and escalated bugs using Bugzilla to discuss with developers
- Identified and troubleshot software and environmental issues by eliminating instabilities

Customer Service Representative (Call Center)

Jun. 2019 - Aug. 2019

MSi Corp- Ottawa, Canada

- Coordinated orders by phone for new Bell installations, moves, adds, changes, and customer win-backs
- Determined and negotiated the best solution, and chose the most appropriate procedure to follow
- Recorded, maintained and retrieved customer's information using Bell ticketing system and databases
- Closed sales and efficiently placed orders to meet customer satisfaction within allotted time frames
- Adhered to call duration and scheduling requirements

Education	
Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Memorial University- St. John's, Newfoundland	2012 - 2018
Diploma in Computer Networking and Internet (Assessed by WES) An-Najah National University - Nablus, Palestine	2006 - 2008
Professional Development	
Master the Linux Command Line (Udemy)	2020
The Complete Web Developer online course (Udemy)	2019
Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP)	2009
Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator (MCSA)	2009
Volunteer Experience	
Ottawa Local Life Leader - Young Adult Cancer Canada(YACC) Ottawa, Canada	March. 2021 - Present
Software Developer - Ready for STEM St. John's, Canada	Jan. 2019 - Apr. 2019
Event Organizer - Young Adult Cancer Canada(YACC) St. John's, Canada	2018 - 2019
Exam Invigilator - International English Language Testing System St. John's, Canada	Nov. 2018